Check it out,this is unbelievable!
你看，太不可思议了
Joey's been holding his breath for almost four minutes.
乔伊已经闷气将近4分钟
You trying to kill me?
猪头，你想闷死我啊？
-I want to ask you something. -What?
菲比，我问你一件事 什么事？
Since I'm moving out, and you're so beautiful...
既然我要搬出去 你又这么美丽…
how about I move in with you?
我搬去跟你住如何？
That would be great, but what do we do about Denise?
太好了，但是狄妮丝怎么办？
-Who's Denise? -My roommate.
谁是狄妮丝？ 我的室友
Your roommate?
你有室友？
Yes,Denise. Denise!
对，狄妮丝，狄妮丝
What is with the secrecy,Phoebe?
你干嘛这么神秘？
What about Denise? She cute?
这个狄妮丝可爱吗？
How can you have a roommate that we don't know about?
我们怎么会不知道你有室友？
Because you never listen to what I say.
也许是因为都没人在听我讲话
I talk about her all the time. Denise!
我一天到晚提起她，狄妮丝！
I'm gonna have an extra room over at my place.
瑞秋，我在想 我那里会多一个房间
-That's true. -Move in with me.
没错 你何不搬来跟我住？
We can stay up late talking, and watch movies.
多好啊 我们可以熬夜谈心，看电影
You know about naked Thursdays, right?
你知道赤裸星期四的规定吧？
Yeah,yeah. I think I'll find my own place.
我还是自己找房子好了
Hey! I thought naked Thursdays was just our thing,man.
我以为赤裸星期四 是我们的专利
The One With Ross' Denial
本集播出：“爱与不爱”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
What did Rachel say when you told her you were still married to her?
你没办注销，瑞秋怎么说？
Oh,that.
那个啊
She took it really well.
她还蛮平静的
-You didn't tell her,did you? -No.
你没说对吧？ 没有
Because you're in love with her.
当然没有，因为你爱她
I am not in love with her. She was upset about having to move out.
我并不爱她 她在为搬家的事难过
If she knew we were still married, she'd have been more upset.
所以我没说，免得她更不开心
So I comforted her. As a friend.
我只以朋友的身分安慰她
You "comforted her"?
什么叫安慰她？
Nothing. I just gave her a hug.
也没什么，我抱了抱她
A classic sign of love, the hug.
拥抱正是爱的表示
It's also a sign of friendship.
也是友情的表现
Not in your case, "Lovey Loverson."
在这里不是，痴情男
It was a hug. Okay?
那只是个拥抱
A simple hug.
一个单纯的拥抱
I was a friend being a friend to a friend.
我只是对朋友尽朋友的心意
Use the word "friend" more.
你太强调朋友了
Did you,or did you not, smell her hair?
告诉我，你有没有闻她的头发
Smell her hair?
闻她的头发？
What if I did?
如果有呢？
Ninety percent of a woman's pheromones come out of her head.
九成的女性费洛蒙散发自头部
That's why women are shorter.
所以女人都比较矮
So that men will fall in love when they hug them.
好让男人在拥抱时爱上她们
Come on,Ross, you're a scientist.
拜托，你是科学家耶
I was hugging her as a friend.
我是以朋友的身分抱她
It's not my fault her hair got in my face.
又不是我把脸埋进她的头发
She's got a lot of it, and it smells all... all...
她的头发很多，有一股…
coconutty.
椰子香
What? It doesn't mean I have feelings for Rachel.
怎样？那不代表我对她有感觉
Maybe it means I have feelings for coconuts.
或许我是对椰子有感觉
Okay,but be careful. Rachel's not in the same place you are.
好，随你怎么说 但你要小心 瑞秋的心情和你不同
If the place you're referring to is being in love...
如果这个心情是指爱情
she is in the same place as me, because I am not in that place.
那她和我的心情一样 因为我不是那个心情
I didn't understand that.
好，我听不懂
Maybe that's because you were speaking the secret language of love.
或许因为你讲的是爱的秘语
-A guy just called for you. -Who was it?
刚才有你的电话 是谁？
I don't know. How about "Thanks for taking the message"?
我哪知？ 你怎么不谢我帮你留言？
When you move in...
等你搬进来
Rachel's room will be empty. Let's talk about what to do with it.
瑞秋的房间就空出来了 要不要来讨论怎么利用？
I think we should have a beautiful guest room...
好啊 我想我们应该弄个漂亮的客房
with a mahogany sleigh bed and bedside tables with fresh flowers.
有红木雪橇床 床头桌上永远插着鲜花
And comment cards so people could tell us how great their stay was.
再摆张卷盖式书桌放上留言卡 让客人表达他们的开心之类的
I really haven't thought about it that much.
我还没有想太多
Well,I like that idea... obviously.
我喜欢这个主意…当然喜欢
I was thinking maybe... maybe it could be a game room.
我在想或许可以弄个游戏房
You can buy old arcade games, like Space lnvaders and Asteroids...
我们可以买旧的游戏机 像太空入侵者和小行星
for $200. The real ones. The big,big,big ones!
只要2百元，正港又大台
No.
不要
You mean "No" as in:
你的意思是“天哪，钱德”
"What an interesting idea. Let's discuss it before we reject it."
“好有趣的主意” “我们先讨论再全盘否定”
I'm sorry.
对不起，当然啦
Interesting idea. But no.
很有趣的主意 谈过了，但是不要
So that's it?
就这样？
I just don't think arcade games go in a beautiful guest room...
漂亮的客房不适合放游戏机
filled with antiques.
漂亮的客房里会有很多古董
Which is why Asteroids is perfect. It's the oldest game.
所以小行星才适合 那是最古老的游戏机
What's wrong with a beautiful guest room?
你对漂亮的客房有什么意见？
I'm not against it.
我没有意见
Especially since everybody we know lives about 30 seconds away.
尤其是我们认识的人都住在方圆数公尺内
Are you mocking me?
你在嘲笑我吗？
No,I'm not mocking you or your beautiful guest room.
我没有在嘲笑你 或是你漂亮的客房
怎么了？
Monica and l had a stupid fight.
没事，摩妮卡和我吵架了
You're still moving in together, right? My ad came out today.
但你们还是要同居吧？ 我的广告今天出来了
"Wanted: Female roommate, nonsmoker,nonugly."
“诚徵女性室友” “不抽烟，不丑”
Nice.
漂亮
I figured it'd be more interesting to have a female roommate.
我想说在你之后 换个女室友会蛮有趣的
Someone I could learn from. Someone who's different than me.
一个我可以学习 和我不一样的人
And what's more different than me, a guy who's not 19...
谁和我最不一样？ 年过19的男人
than a girl who is 19?
还是19岁的女孩？
Not just a hatrack,my friend.
我可不是草包
Phoebe,I have to ask you..
菲比，我想问…
I'm swamped right now.
嘘…我正在忙
You're just staring into space.
你只是在发呆
I'm trying to move that pencil.
我想移动那支铅笔
-This one? -lt worked!
这支吗？ 成功了
Phoebe,this whole apartment thing is a nightmare.
菲比，找房子真是恶梦
Anything I can afford comes with a roommate who is a freak. Look.
我租得起的地方都有怪胎室友 你看嘛
"Wanted: Female roommate, nonsmoker,nonugly."
“诚徵女性室友” “不抽烟，不丑”
That's probably some 12-year-old kid trying to get girls to call.
可能是想跟女生讲电话的小鬼
There's nothing. This city is full.
没房子了，纽约都住满了
Wait! Look at this!
等等，这里有
"Two bedroom,two bath. Must be nonsmoker. Satan worshipers okay."
“两房两卫，不得抽烟” “拜撒旦者可”
Yeah,but it's on the ground floor.
不过是一楼
-Rach,you still looking for a place? -Yeah,why?
瑞秋，你还在找房子？ 对，怎样？
This guy,Warren,from the museum is going on a dig for two years.
好，我们博物馆有个华伦 要去参与挖掘工作2年
He's got this great place he needs to sublet. You interested?
他有个漂亮的家要转租 你有兴趣吗？
Great! I'd love to live at Warren's. I love Warren!
听起来好棒 我愿意住华伦家，我爱华伦
Oh,wait. Is he the guy that asked you for naked pictures of me?
等等，是他跟你要我的裸照吗
That doesn't matter, he won't be there!
反正他要走了
-Thank you! -Don't thank me.
谢谢你 别谢我
Thank the volcano that erupted thousands of years ago...
要就谢那座火山几千年前爆发
killing, but perfectly preserving, an entire civilization.
毁灭却也保存了一整个文明
Here's Warren's number.
这是华伦的电话
This is great. I'm gonna call him right now! Thank you!
太好了，我现在就打给他 谢谢你
Okay, you go call him.
好，快去吧
I saw it.
我看到了
What are you talking about?
我不知道你在说什么
I'm talking about what you already know but won't admit.
我在说你知道却不肯承认的事
You love her again. You re-love her.
你又爱上她了，你重复爱她
I do not re-love her.
我没有重复爱她
I can't believe you won't just admit it.
你居然这么嘴硬
Promise me you won't do anything stupid.
总之你千万别做蠢事
We're just friends now. Why would I do anything stupid?
我们现在只是朋友 我为什么要做蠢事？
The apartment is already subletted.
房子已经租出去了
It's hopeless. I'll never find anything.
没希望了，我找不到房子了
Live with me.
你可以来跟我住
-What? -What?!
什么？ 什么？
What?
怎样？
Are you serious?
天哪，你是说真的吗？
I would love to live with you. That's great. Thank you.
我求之不得，太好了，谢谢你
I'm just glad I could help you out.
有帮到你就好
Wow,I'm so happy for you guys. This is so, so, not stupid.
我真替你们高兴 这真是非常的不蠢
Ross, you have no idea what this means to me.
罗斯，这对我太重要了
I was gonna be homeless. You just saved me. You're my hero.
我差点就要流落街头 你救了我，你是我的英雄
Hero? I don't know. Well, all right.
说英雄就太…好吧
I have to go tell Monica what a wonderful brother she has.
我要去告诉摩妮卡 她的哥哥有多棒
Oh,please.
别这样
You're gonna say things now, aren't you?
你又有话要说了吧？
No. No,I won't.
没有
But I should tell you this.
但是我告诉你
The same thing happened to my roommate,Denise.
我的室友狄妮丝就是这样
She moved in with a guy who was secretly married to her.
她搬去跟一个偷娶她的人住
He said he didn't love her, but he really did. And it just blew up.
他嘴上说不爱，其实很爱她 他嘴上说不爱，其实很爱她
And that's how she ended up living with me.
后来事情爆发 所以她才搬来跟我住
Okay, that's a lie.
好吧，我骗你的
-You don't have a roommate. -Denise!
你才没有室友 狄妮丝
No one ever listens to me!
都没有人听我讲话
Listen,I'm sorry about before. I don't need a game room.
刚才很抱歉，我不需要游戏房
I only played those games because I couldn't get girls. Now I can get..
我以前把不到马子才去打游戏 现在我把得到了…
Now I have you.
现在我有了你
No,not that I think I have you...
我并不是把你当成
or think of you as property in any sort of way. I see women....
或想成一件财产 我对女人…
Stop it,Chandler.
别再说了
I'm sorry too.
我也很抱歉
-Really? -Yeah. Oh,yes.
真的？ 对，当然
We can think of something to do with the room together.
我们不必弄一个客房 我们可以一起想要怎么利用
Great idea. We can easily think of a way for us both to enjoy the room.
好主意 要做到皆大欢喜很容易
Totally.
就是啊
-We don't have to decide now. -Good.
我们不必现在想 好
Let's think about changes we can make in the living room.
不如来想想客厅要怎么变化
Changes?
变化？
We'll have to move some furniture to make room for my chair.
对，我们得移动一些砭 来放我的椅子
You're bringing the Barcalounger over here?
你要把懒人椅搬过来？
Is that a problem?
有问题吗？
It's just that they're a set and should stay together.
那是一组的，应该摆在一起
That's cool. I'll bring them both over.
那好，那我就都搬过来
You're taking them away from their home.
你是要它们离开老家
I get it. I get nothing. Nothing here is mine. Everything is yours.
好，我懂了，这里没我的东西 只有你的东西
I'll get up in the morning,put on your clothes and go off to work!
我早上起床就穿上你的衣服 然后去上班
Yeah,that's it. Everything will be mine. Nothing will be yours.
没错，这里只有我的东西 没有你的，这是我说的
I'm talking about the Barcalounger.
拜托！我是在讲懒人椅
It doesn't match. Where will it go?
它跟这里不搭，你要摆哪里？
In the game room!
游戏房里
It is not my fault your chairs are incredibly ugly.
你的椅子丑到爆又不是我的错
That's fine.
好
I won't bring the chairs. I won't bring anything!
我不搬椅子过来 我什么都不搬过来
I wouldn't want to ruin the ambiance over here at grandma's place!
我可不想破坏老奶奶家的调调
Everything on your application looks really good.
你的条件看起来很好
Just one last question.
最后一个问题
Will your friends be over here, partying and hanging out?
你和你朋友 会不会常来这里狂欢聚会？
Don't worry. I'm not a party girl.
放心，我不太爱玩
Don't just be blurting stuff out.
别想都不想就说
I want you to really think about your answers.
我要你想清楚再答
Call off the roommate search. Hi. I'll be living here.
你不必找室友了 你好，我要住在这里
Ignore him. He's just some guy who wants the apartment.
别理他，他很想住进来
But he's not going to get it.
但我不会选他
You took down the shower curtain?
你干嘛把浴帘拿掉？
That thing was a hazard!
那个东西很危险
I'm very safety conscious.
我很注重安全
I was just clearing some space for your stuff.
我正在清一些空间给你
Thanks.
谢谢
But listen,Monica and Chandler had a big fight and they're not moving in.
但我刚去找摩妮卡 她和钱德大吵一架不同居了
What do you mean, not moving in? They're still moving in, right?
什么叫不同居了？ 他们还是要同居吧？
No, they just had a big blowout over what to do with my room.
不，他们为了怎么利用空房 大吵一架
Over a stupid room?
就为了一个烂房间？
I feel kind of bad for them,but now I don't have to move in here!
我也有点替他们可惜 却又很高兴不必搬过来了
Oh, no. Yeah, that part's great.
没错，这一点的确很棒
What's all this about you guys fighting?
你们两个是在吵什么？
Is this really over a room?
真的就为了一个房间？
That is so silly.
真是太傻了
-We can handle this. -Apparently not.
罗斯，我们自己可以摆平 显然不行
And I can't stand by and watch two people I care about so much...
我不能坐视两个我关心的人
be hurt by something that is so silly.
为了这么傻的事伤感情
Enough of the silliness.
别再傻了
Tell her to stop being silly.
你叫她别傻啊
好
Two very good points.
双方都有理
I've known you both a long time.
我认识你们两个很久了
And I've never seen either of you one-millionth as happy...
你们在一起之后
as you've been since you got together.
比以前快乐一百万倍
Do you really want to throw that all away over a room?
你们真的要为了一个房间 放弃这一切？
That is so silly.
多傻啊
What's more important,love...
什么比较重要 爱情...
or silliness?
还是傻气？
Well,we are fond of the silliness.
我们喜欢傻气
But we also have a soft spot for the love.
但面对爱情也会心软
-Love is the best medicine. -That's "laughter."
爱是万灵药 欢笑才是吧？
-Why do you do it? -I don't know.
你为什么这样？ 我不知道
Now, Chandler, you want to live with Monica, right?
钱德，你想跟摩妮卡住吧？
Yeah, I do.
对
And,Mon,you want to live with Chandler?
摩妮卡，你想跟钱德住吧？
Yes.
对
A verbal contract is binding in the state of New York!
很好，口头契约 在纽约州有约束力
So I understand you're looking for a place?
我听说你在找房子
No, I'm staying put.
不，我不搬了
I was going to offer you my apartment.
我本来打算找你来我家住
Why? Where you going?
为什么？你要去哪里？
I don't know.
我不知道
瑞秋
You won't believe it.
说了你一定不信
Monica and Chandler are moving in again.
钱德和摩妮卡又要同居了
That's great news, right? I mean, for them, right?
真是太好了… 对他们来说，对吧？
But on the bright side, we get to be roommates again.
不过好处是我们又能当室友了
Yeah. You know,about that....
是啊，关于这件事…
I really appreciate your offer to let me move in and everything...
我很感谢你主动提议，但是…
but don't you think it'll be weird?
你不觉得会很怪吗？
Why? Why would it.... Why would it be weird?
为什么？为…为什么会怪？
Well, you know, because of us.
因为我们
Because of our history.
因为我们的过去
No!
不会 不会吗？
No,no!
不会
It would only be weird if we were still in "that place."
除非我们还余情未了
Are you still in that place?
你还余情未了吗？
-No,not at all. -Good. Me neither.
一点也没有 很好，我也没有
So it's not a problem.
那就没问题了
We're just two friends who happen to be roommates.
我们只是刚好是室友的朋友
Okay, but eventually you and I will be dating.
好，但我们迟早会约会
Really? We are?
是吗？
Yeah. I'll have a boyfriend and you'll have a girlfriend.
是啊，我会有男朋友 你会有女朋友
That'd be great.
那太好了
But if you think it'll be okay, we'll just work out a system.
不过如果你觉得无所谓 我们就想一套做法
It'll be like in college. I'll hang a sign on the door:
就像大学时代 我在门上挂个牌子
"Come back later. I'm getting lucky."
“暂且回避，正在炒饭”
Yeah,I didn't think of that.
我想都没想过
So are you sure about this whole moving-in thing?
你们确定要住在一起？
It's a really big step. And what's the rush?
这是很大的进展，急什么呢？
That's very funny.
真好笑
He's being silly because he knows we enjoy the silliness.
他在装傻 因为他知道我们喜欢傻气
No,I'm serious. Think about it. You move in.
我是说真的，你们想想 你搬进来
You start fighting over game rooms. Next thing you know, you break up.
你们为了游戏房的事吵架 接下来就会分手
It was just a stupid fight about a room.
罗斯，你说得对 吵那种架很蠢
There are no stupid fights!
一点也不蠢
This isn't about the room.
重点不是房间
This is about what the room represents.
而是房间代表什么
And unfortunately, this room could destroy you!
很不幸的 这个房间会毁了你们
-I'm not so worried. -Me neither.
我没那么担心 我也是
Fine. It's your life!
好吧，这是你们的人生
I just don't want to see you break up.
我只是不想看到你们分手
Which you will do if you move in together.
你们要是同居就会分手
But if that's what you want, there's nothing I can do.
但你们想这样，我也没办法
Don't do it!
不要同居
-You still want to move in together? -Of course.
你还是想搬进来吧？ 当然
Ross didn't scare you?
罗斯没吓到你？
Scared me out of wanting to live with him.
吓得我死也不敢跟他住
-I gotta show you something. -Okay.
我给你看个东西 好
Oh,my God! Someone's killed Square Man!
天哪，正方形人被杀了
The Barcalounger can go here.
我觉得懒人椅可以放这里
You can see the TV,and it's still walking distance to the kitchen.
你可以看电视
Oh,that's so sweet.
离厨房又够近 真周到
I want to show you something too.
我也有事要说 好
You know those big road signs that say "merge"?
你知道道路会合的标志吧？
I thought we could get one of those signs and hang it over our bed.
我想我们可以弄一个挂在床头
Because that's you and I together.
因为你和我就是那样
"Merge!"
合而为一
-I love that! -Really?
天哪，我好喜欢喔 真的？
"No!"
才怪
I found you in my bed
我发现你在我床上
How'd you wind up there?
你怎么会在那里？
You are a mystery
你真是个谜
Little black curly hair
小黑卷毛男
Little black,little black, little black
小黑卷毛…小黑卷毛
Little black curly hair
小黑卷毛男
If you want to receive e-mails about my upcoming shows...
如果想收到我的演出讯息
please give me money so I can buy a computer.
请捐钱给我，让我买电脑
Where are the other guys?
其他人呢？
Well,Monica and Chandler are occupied.
摩妮卡和钱德在忙
-Fighting? -The other thing.
吵架？ 不，是忙别的
It's great they worked things out.
真高兴他们能和好
There's no breaking them up, is there?
谁也别想拆散他们，对吧？
Can I borrow the key to your house so I can go make a copy?
可以跟你借钥匙去打一副吗？
-Here. -Thank you.
当然可以，拿去 谢谢
Are you sure? Once I make a copy, there's no turning back.
你确定吗？ 打了钥匙就不能反悔了
Yeah, I'm sure. Now get out of here before I change my mind.
我确定 趁我改变心意前快去吧
You think moving in with Rachel is a good idea?
罗斯，跟瑞秋住真的好吗？
I've been back and forth.
我也在摇摆不定
Well,maybe you should go back.
也许你应该摆回去
She moves in, and before you know it...
瑞秋搬进去
you're right where you don't want to be,back together.
不知不觉间你们就又复合了
I don't think so. She's already talking about dating other guys.
应该不会 她已经在谈交男朋友的事
That's not going to work out. She'll come home all weepy...
不会有结果的 她会哭着回家
and you'll be telling her, "Oh, that's okay. You'll find someone."
你会告诉她 “没关系，你会找到好男人”
And then, bam! She finds you!
接着砰！她找到了你
Maybe you're right.
也许你说得对
Ross,she is definitely gonna fall in love with you again.
她绝对会再爱上你
Is that what you want?
这样你也愿意吗？
Is that what I want?
我愿意吗？
Yes.
是的
Here she comes. I'm gonna make your life much easier.
她来了，我来替你省点事
The place was closed, so I'll copy it later.
五金行打烊了，改天再打
Or not.
或是别打了
Why don't you move in with me?
瑞秋，你就搬来跟我住嘛
Whoa, Joey!
乔伊 等等…
Look, I know I scared you with that whole naked-Thursdays thing...
瑞秋，我知道赤裸星期四 把你吓跑了
but we don't have to do that.
但是我们也可以不那样做
It would be easier to move across the hall.
搬到对面确实比较轻松
Unless you're thinking about naked Wednesdays.
慢着 除非你想改成赤裸星期三
Thursday's clearly not good for you. Pick a day!
你不喜欢星期四，那就挑一天
Come on in. Thanks for coming back.
请进，谢谢你再跑一趟
There's a lot of people interested in the room.
有很多人想租
But I've narrowed it down, and you're one of the finalists.
但我经过筛选 你是最后人选之一
-Great! -Before I decide...
太好了
I want to be sure our personalities match.
在做决定之前 我想确定我们合得来
So I made up a little test.
所以我发明了一个小测验
I'll say a word,and you say the first thing that comes to mind.
我说一个词 你就说出第一个联想
-I can do that. -Okay, here we go.
没问题 好，那我们开始
-Pillow. -Fight.
枕头 仗
Very good.
很好
"G."
G
-String? -Excellent!
丁字 裤？ 非常好
Doggy.
狗
-Kitten? -Sorry!
猫？ 很抱歉
So close, though. Bye-bye!
就差那么一点点，再见